Passchendaele is a drama, romance, war film directed by Paul Gross.
Sergeant Michael Dunne fights in the 10th Battalion, AKA The "Fighting Tenth" with the 1st Canadian Division and participated in all
major Canadian battles of the war, and set the record for highest number of individual bravery awards for a single battle
Michael Dunne, played by Paul Gross.
Sarah Mann, played by Caroline Dhavernas.
David Mann, played by Joe Dinicol.
Cassie Walker, played by Meredith Bailey.
Colonel Ormand, played by Adam J. Harrington.
Royster, played by Gil Bellows.
Passchendaele is a 2008 Canadian war film, written,
co-produced, directed by, and starring Paul Gross.
The film, which was shot in Calgary, Alberta, Fort Macleod, Alberta, and in Belgium, focuses on the experiences of a Canadian soldier, Michael Dunne, at the Battle
of Passchendaele, also known as the Third Battle of Ypres, inspired by stories that Gross heard from his grandfather, a First World War soldier.
The film had its premiere at the 2008 Toronto International Film Festival on
September 4, 2008, when it also had the honour of opening the festival.
The film received a mixed reception upon release.
On March 2, 2009, Paul Gross was honoured for his film Passchendaele, winning that year's
National Arts Centre Award for achievement over the past performance year.
The film won five awards at the 29th Genie Awards, including Best Picture, and also
received the Golden Reel Award for Canada's top-grossing film of 2008.
The film explores themes of canada, nurse, world war i, battle, platoon.
The tone is emotional.